Finding Aid for the Collection of Turkish Manuscripts LSC.0896
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collection of Turkish manuscripts
circa 1600-1900
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0896
104.0 Linear Feet (204 boxes and 2 flat boxes)
Collection consists of manuscripts of Turkish folk poetry. The entire collection is in Turkish.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942328913606533
Other Finding Aids
A digital copy of Volume 12, Catalog of Turkish Urdu and Collected Multi-Lingual Middle Eastern Manuscripts in Special Collections is available at this link: Catalog of Persian and Arabic manuscripts in Special Collections.
Manuscripts -- Turkey.; Folk poetry, Turkish
- Title (Romanized): Macmua-i latif Title (English): Charming anthology Alternative titles: ?????? ????, Majmuah la?if, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 1; 251 leaves: paper; 147 x 95 mm. bound to 148 x 98 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Brown morocco, with marble paste-downs, green leather spine, and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; chart on 250a. (Box 1)
  Scope and Content
  Collection of Persian and Turkish belles- lettres, mostly Sufi. Includes the works of Nev î (1533-1599), Suhî (writing in 1580's), Jami (1414-1492), Sádi, ?Abd Allah An?ari (1006-1089), and others.
- Title (Romanized): Tezkeretü's-Suarâ Uniform title: R?za Tezkiresi Title (English): Remembrance of the poets Alternative titles: ????? ???????, Tezkere-yi R?za, Tadhkirat al- shúara, Date: 1643 November; Manuscript number: 2; 41 leaves: paper; 205 x 125 mm. bound to 207 x 127 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Brown paper over boards, with brown leather spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; chart on 250a. (Box 1)
  Lives and works of Ottoman poets including Ottoman Sultans from Mehmet II to Murad III. The original was written in 1640 (41a) and dedicated (1a) to Sultan Ibrahim (1640-1648).
- Title (Romanized): Tezkere Uniform title: Tezkere-yi Riyazi Title (English): Remembrance Alternative titles: ?????? Tadhkirah, Date: 1636; Manuscript number: 3; 99 leaves: paper; 198 x 136 mm. bound to 200 x 139 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Burgundy leather with marble paste-downs, blind-stamped, with leather fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some marginalia. (Box 1)
  Lives and works of Ottoman poets, arranged alphabetically by poet's name. Composition date was 1607 (99a).
- Title (Romanized): Zahrat al-muta'ahhilin Title (English): The flower of married folks Alternative titles: ???? ?????????, Date: 1624; Manuscript number: 4; 47 leaves: paper; 210 x 156 mm. bound to 208 x 154 mm.; Layout: 19/13 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh and Nastál?q. Binding: Brown paper overboard with leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some marginalia. (Box 1)
  Theology and jurisprudence. The manuscript contains two other titles, a collection of poems, and a work on the fundamentals and the secondary matters of religion.
- Title (Romanized): [Macmua-i siir] Title (English): [Collection of poetry], Date: 1723; Manuscript number: 5; 51 leaves: paper; 210 x 156 mm. bound to 208 x 154 mm.; Layout: Average 17 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Burgundy leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; leaves separated from the spine; stains and water damage; some marginalia. (Box 1)
  Provenance
  Several ownership stamps on front endpapers
  The manuscript contains a number of musical lyrics as well as verses by Fuzulî (1495?-1556), Emir Osman Efendi Hasimi (d. 1594), and perhaps others.
- Title (Romanized): el-Edvar fi ilmi'l-musiki Title (English): Pieces on the science of music Alternative titles: ?????? ?? ??? ????????, al- adwar fi ilm al-musiqi, Date: [18--]?; Manuscript number: 6; 10 leaves: paper; 220 x 160 mm. bound to 230 x 162 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Burgundy leather with gilt borders, faded. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some charts and sketches of instruments; the script is something between Nastá l?q and riqa. (Box 1)
  Short treatise on musical scales and instruments inspired by the classical Arabic treatise on music by al- Farabi.
- Title (Romanized): Ahlak-i ala'i Title (English): Glorious ethics Alternative titles: ???? ????, Akhlaq ala'i, Date: Before 1658; Manuscript number: 7; 10 leaves: paper; 223 x 124 mm. bound to 222 x 124 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Nastál?q. Binding: Brown leather, gilt inlaid, with burgundy leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; enclosed in red borders. (Box 1)
  Ownership stamp of ?aji A?mad Khalifah, dated 1658, on 1a.
  Belles-lettres on the rules for proper behavior by monarchs. Dedicated to Sultan Süleyman the Magnificent. The author has drawn inspirations from similar works by Tusi, Husayn Vaiz Kashifi, and Dawwani.
- Title (Romanized): Hulviyat Title (English): Sweet things Alternative titles: ?????? ?ulwiyat-i shahi fi al-furu {in Kâtip Çelebi Kashf al- ?unun, Date: Before 1650; Manuscript number: 8; 198 leaves: paper; 291 x 183 mm. bound to 292 x 205 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with leather stripe over spine; frayed and disintegrating. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; frayed around the edges. (Box 1)
  Biography
  The author of this book is better known to history as Ismail Isfendiyaroglu, brother-in-law of the Ottoman Sultan Mehmed II who conquered Constantinople in 1453. Ismail wrote this book on religious precepts after the sultan removed him from the rule of the city of Sinop on the Black Sea coast.
  On religious practices and doctrine such as ablution, prayer, mosques, and religious holidays. Translated from various sources for the benefit of "those who do not know Arabic and Persian". Author's name contains two other words which, transliterated by Arabic standard, read "Yaman Jandar {which is Turkish "Çandar"}". The original dates to the early fifteenth-century (DP reference below). [See also number 115]
- Title (Romanized): Menak?p-i Emir Sultan Title (English): The lives of Emir Sultan Alternative titles: ????? ???? ?????, Manaqib amir sul?an, Date: 1640; Manuscript number: 9; 149 leaves: paper; 269 x 174 mm. bound to 268 x 178 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown paper over boards, with leather stripe over spine; frayed and disintegrating. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some water damage. (Box 2)
  Collection of biographical stories about an early fifteenth-century Sufi shaykh by the name of Emir Sultan Buhari (Sayyid Mu?ammad al- Bukhari). The author gives the date of 1562 for the composition (3b). The text is not the same as that of Senâyî's.
- Title (Romanized): Umdetü'l-Islam Title (English): The pillar of Islam Alternative titles: ???? ??????, 'Imad al-Islam,' Umdat al-Islam, Date: 1621 September; Manuscript number: 10; 206 leaves: paper; 281 x 189 mm. bound to 280 x 191 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind-stamped, with fore-edge flap; frayed and almost separated. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; some water and termite damage; marginalia in black and red. (Box 2)
  Islam: Hanafi doctrine/popular belief. Translated into Turkish by the author from the Persian work of 'Abd al-'Aziz Farsi (2a) covering topics such as faith, prayer, lawful and unlawful things, etc.
- Title (Romanized): Envarü'l-âsikîn Uniform title: Envar ül-asikin / Envar ül-âsikîn Title (English): Light-rays of lovers Alternative titles: ????? ????????, Anwar al-ashiqin, Date: 1795 July; Manuscript number: 11; 344 leaves: paper; 268 x 182 mm. bound to 268 x 203 mm.; Layout: 16 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind-stamped, with stripe over spine, and fore-edge flap; frayed and slashed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, all within red borders; some stains. (Box 3)
  Author also known as "Bican, Yaz?c?oglu A?met".
  Translation of an Arabic work by his brother (listed in Kâtip Çelebi's Kashf al-?unun as Magharib al-zaman li-ghurub al-ashya' fi al-'ayn wa al-'iyan), completed during the reign of Mehmet II in February 1451 in the city of Gallipoli (343a). Islam: doctrine and belief regarding the world, God, prophets, angels, signs of judgment day, etc.
- Title (Romanized): [Müfredat-i Ibn-i Beytar] Title (English): [The inventory of Ibn al-Bay?ar] Alternative titles: [Mufradat Ibn al-Bay?ar], Date: [16--]; Manuscript number: 12; 306 leaves: paper; 265 x 193 mm. bound to 265 x 195 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, blind-stamped, torn, frayed, and slashed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red, all within red borders; extensive marginalia in several hands in Ottoman Turkish and Greek; leaves missing from the beginning and the end. (Box 3)
  This is a Turkish translation of the Arabic pharmaceutical inventory of Ibn al-Bay?ar ('Abd Allah ibn A?mad, d. 1248) entitled al- Jam? li-mufradat al-adwiyah wa-al-aghdiyah. The texts is dedicated to a certain Anatolian lord named Umur Bey.
- Title (Romanized): [Fütuh'üs-Sam ] Title (English): [Conquests of Syria] Alternative titles: ????? ???? ?????, Tercüme-yi fütuh üs-Sam, Futu? al-sham, Date: [17--]?; Manuscript number: 13; 237 leaves: paper; 245 x 165 mm. bound to 2525 x 182 mm.; Layout: 15 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black cloth and pink paper over boards quarter binding; fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red, all within red borders; several pages torn (chewed) from the top edge; some stains; leaves from the beginning and the end of the manuscript are missing. (Box 4)
  This is an early Turkish translation of an Arabic original entitled Futu? al-Sham by Waqidi (747 or 8- 823).
- Title (Romanized): Bag-i bihist Title (English): Garden of paradise Alternative titles: ??? ????, Bagh-i bihisht, Date: 1659; Manuscript number: 14; 248 leaves: paper; 280 x 190 mm. bound to 285 x 190 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with purple canvass on spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red, the scribe's ending rhymes in red; first page enclosed in red borders; some water damage. (Box 4)
  Composition in verse on mysticism. The original was finished on Friday 12 February 1638 (247a).
- Title (Romanized): Teshil Title (English): Facilitation Alternative titles: ????? Ilyasiyah fi al- ?ibb, Tashil, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 15; 172 leaves: paper; 294 x 190 mm. bound to 292 x 195 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with purple canvass on spine; fore-edge flap separated. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red; notes on leaves between titles; marginalia; final leaves stained. (Box 4)
  Medicine. The first author's full name is listed as: Haci Pasa H?z?r b. Ali b. Hattap Ayd?ni. There are 4 other works in the manuscript, all on medicine.
- Title (Romanized): Niyazü'l-müznibin Title (English): Needment of the guilty Alternative titles: ???? ????????, Niyaz al-mudhnibin, Niyaz al-muznibin, Date: 1733; Manuscript number: 16; 173 leaves: paper; 310 x 200 mm. bound to 310 x 210 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with burgundy leather stripe on edges; fore-edge flap; termite damage. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red; in red borders; stained. (Box 5)
  Islam: work on religious requirements in rhyming Turkish couplets. Author had begun the work (9a) during the reign of Murad III (r. 1574- 1595).
- Title (Romanized): Cevahirü'l-ahbar Title (English): Jewels of reports Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Jawahir al-akhbar, Date: 1526 December; Manuscript number: 17; 252 leaves: paper; 298 x 195 mm. bound to 310 x 210 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black buckram. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red; illustration on 227b; frayed around the edges; stained. (Box 5)
  On prayers as well as prophetic reports and stories. Written by several hands.
- Title (Romanized): Garib-nâme Title (English): Book of strange [things] Alternative titles: ???? ????, Gharib'namah, Date: [14--]?; Manuscript number: 18; 288 leaves: paper; 243 x 159 mm. bound to 241 x 158 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown paper over boards with remnant of brown leather stripe over spine; front board missing. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, headings in Persian and in red ink; worn; beginning leaves missing; final leaves supplied later; leaf 1 is torn out; page numbers written in reverse. (Box 6)
  Long poem on Sufism in ten books. Preface in Persian, but including Hebrew verses in Arabic script. Composition of the original was in 1329 (288a).
- Title (Romanized): Hulviyat Title (English): Sweet things Alternative titles: ??????, ?ulwiyat shahi fi al-furu {in Kâtip Çelebi, "Kashf al- ?unun, Date: 1537 February; Manuscript number: 19; 333 leaves: paper; 255 x 178 mm. bound to 260 x 180 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Faux blue Morocco with fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; enclosed in red borders; very well preserved. (Box 6)
  On religious practices and doctrine. Same title as mss. 8 above.
- Title (Romanized): Garib-nâme Title (English): Book of strange [things] Alternative titles: ???? ????, Gharib'namah, Date: 1457 December; Manuscript number: 20; 314 leaves: paper; 244 x 164 mm. bound to 256 x 176 mm.; Layout: 15 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with leather stripe on spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; text on some pages enclosed in red borders; last few leaves written in later. (Box 7)
  Long poem on Sufism in ten books. Preface in Persian, but including Hebrew verses in Arabic script. Composition of the original was in 1329.
- Title (Romanized): Cilti'l-evvel min tefsir-i Abi'l-leys Title (English): Volume one of the exegesis of Abu al-Layth Alternative titles: ??? ???? ?? ????? ??? ????, Jild al-awwal min tafsir-i Abu al-Layth, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 21; 351 leaves: paper; 264 x 178 mm. bound to 256 x 176 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Burgundy leather, blind-stamped, with gilt edges and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and Koranic phrases in red, and title line of text in gold; some termite damage. (Box 7)
  This translation is attributed variously to Musa bin Hac? Hüseyn Izniki, d. 1434; Ahmet Sâlih; Ibn' Arabshah, A?mad ibn Mu?ammad, 1392-1450; and Ahmed Dâi, fl. 1387-1421.
  Part of a Turkish translation of Abu al-Layth al- ?amarqandi's Koranic exegesis known as the Ba?r al- 'ulum.
- Title (Romanized): Muhammediye Title (English): [The book] of Mu?ammad Alternative titles: ??????? ????????, al-Risalah al- Mu?amadiyah, Date: 1592 May; Manuscript number: 22; 282 leaves: paper; 282 x 187 mm. bound to 282 x 195 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, with fore-edge flap; frayed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red, enclosed in red borders; some leaves separating. (Box 8)
  Islam: doctrine and belief regarding the world, God, prophets, angels, signs of judgment day, etc. A verse translation into Turkish of the author's Magharib al-zaman, translated also by his brother into Turkish prose (Envar ül-âsikîn. See mss. 11 above). The verse translation was completed in August 1449 (276b).
- Title (Romanized): Tevârih-i Âl-i Osman Uniform title: Tarih-i Nisanc? Mehmet Pasa Title (English): The histories of the Ottoman house Alternative titles: ?????? ?? ?????, Tawarikh al-? Uthman, Tavarikh al-#x03AF; Usman, Date: Before 1669; Manuscript number: 23; 247 leaves: paper; 254 x 150 mm. bound to 253 x 147 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, gilt-inlaid, with gilt-inlaid fore-edge flap; frayed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red, enclosed in red borders; 1b and 2a gilt-borders. (Box 8)
  Süleyman Bey, commander of the Circassians (his name included in the title and his ownership stamp on 1a).
  A chronological history of the Ottoman dynasty up to the enthronement of Murad III.
- Title (Romanized): Umdetü'l-Islam Title (English): The pillar of Islam Alternative titles: ???? ??????, ?Imad al-Islam, 'Umdat al-Islam, Date: 1502 February; Manuscript number: 24; 214 leaves: paper; 272 x 188 mm. bound to 270 x 190 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, gilt-inlaid, with leather stripe over spine. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and passages in red, some marginalia. (Box 9)
  Islam: Hanafi doctrine/popular belief. Translated into Turkish by the author from the Persian work of 'Abd al-'Aziz Farsi (2a) covering topics such as faith, prayer, lawful and unlawful things, etc. Same as mss. 10 above and 36, 43, 56, and 67 below.
- Title (Romanized): [Serh-i Beharistan-i Câmi] Title (English): [Commentary on the Baharistan of Jami], Date: 1593 April; Manuscript number: 25; 110 leaves: paper; 278 x 188 mm. bound to 274 x 187 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Diwani. Binding: Marble paper over boards. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, underlining and punctuations in red; some marginalia. (Box 9)
  Form of author's name from Osmanl? Müellifleri, V. II: 394. The death-date is wrong.
  A Turkish commentary on the work of the fifteenth century Persian Sufi poet Jami (1414-1492). The text was composed sometime during the reign of Murad III (r. 1574-95).
- Title (Romanized): Tercüman-i Kur'an Title (English): Translation of the Koran Alternative titles: ?????? ????, Tercüme-yi tefsir-i Abi'l-leys, Tarjumat Qur'an, Date: 1815; Manuscript number: 26; 578 leaves: paper; 225 x 152 mm. bound to 225 x 157 mm.; Layout: 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind stamped, with yellow paste-downs, and fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages red, enclosed in gilt borders; 1b illuminated. (Box 9)
  A translation of the Koran. However, a note on the front endpaper, and Danish'pazhuh identify the text as the translation of the exegesis of Abu al-Layth al-?amarqandi (see mss. 21 above). The original was composed in 1689.
- Title (Romanized): Müfredat-i Ibn-i Beytar Title (English): The inventory of Ibn al-Bay?ar Alternative titles: ???? ?????? ??? ?????, Kitap-i Müfredat-i Ibn-i Beytar, Mufradat Ibn al-Bay?ar, Date: 1846; Manuscript number: 27; 143 leaves: paper; 276 x 194 mm. bound to 280 x 194 mm.; Layout: 19 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Green cloth over boards, with fore-edge flap; tearing. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked passages in red; bottom edge title; termite damage; leaves separating. (Box 10)
  This is a Turkish translation of the pharmaceutical inventory of Ibn al-Bay?ar ('Abd Allah ibn A?mad, d. 1248) entitled al- Jami li-mufradat al-adwiyah wa-al-aghdiyah. The texts is dedicated to a certain Anatolian lord named Umur Bey.
- Title (Romanized): Feraidü'l-fevaid fi beyani'l-akaid Uniform title: Aminet serhi: feraid ül-fevaid fi beyan ul-akaid Title (English): Unique things of benefits in the explanation of opinions Alternative titles: ????? ??????? ?? ???? ???????, Feraid ü-fevaid fi beyan il-akaid, Fara'id al-fawa'id fi bayan al- aqa'id, Date: 1824; Manuscript number: 28; 143 leaves: paper; 265 x 174 mm. bound to 265 x 180 mm.; Layout: 17 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Brown leather, inlaid, gilt borders, and with fore-edge flap; frayed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, enclosed in red borders; bottom edge title; termite damage. (Box 10)
  He is also listed as Kad?zade, Ahmed ibn Muhammed Emin Efendi, 1720-1782 (Hollis).
  A compilation and translation into Turkish on matters of belief in God, angels, scriptures, prophets, judgment day, and destiny. A number of Arabic books with that title (but apparently not the present text) in Kâtip Çelebi's Kashf al-?unun.
- Title (Romanized): Takvim Uniform title: Takvim üt-tevarih li-Kâtib Çelebi Title (English): Calendar Alternative titles: Taqwim? ?????, Date: 1748; Manuscript number: 29; 45 leaves: paper; 285 x 182 mm. bound to 284 x 182 mm.; Layout: 23 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Burgundy leather, blind stamped, frayed. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, enclosed in red borders; charts; bottom edge title; termite damage; marginalia and notes. (Box 10)
  This is Kâtib Çelebi's manual for collating dates according to a variety of calendars. Manuscript incomplete with many charts unfilled.
- Title (Romanized): Dürretü't-taç Uniform title: Dürret üt-taç Title (English): Pearl of the crown Alternative titles: ??? ?????, Dürret üt- taç fi sahib-ül miraç, Durrat al-taj, Date: 1748; Manuscript number: 30; 156 leaves: paper; 296 x 176 mm. bound to 298 x 187 mm.; Layout: 27 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, blind stamped, gilt borders, fore-edge flap. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red; enclosed in gold borders; 1b illustrated. (Box 10)
  The second part of Veysî's biography of the prophet Muhammad. The manuscript also contains the continuation of this text by Yusuf Nâbi.
- Title (Romanized): Tarik-i bzdh(?) fi ilmi'r-remil Title (English): The bzdh(?) path of geomancy Alternative titles: ???? ???? ?? ??? ?????, ?ariq bzd?(?) fi ?ilm al-raml, Date: 1760; Manuscript number: 31; 115 leaves: paper; 304 x 180 mm. bound to 303 x 184 mm.; Layout: Average 26 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, inlaid, with fore-edge flap; faded and tearing. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words in red and faded green; enclosed in black borders. (Box 11)
  This is anthology of works on geomancy. The manuscript contains four other titles.
- Title (Romanized): Cevahirü'l-ahbar Title (English): Jewels of reports Alternative titles: ????? ??????, Jawahir al-akhbar, Date: [16--]?; Manuscript number: 32; 318 leaves: paper; 286 x 202 mm. bound to 283 x 190 mm.; Layout: Average 21 lines of text per page. Script: Naskh. Binding: Black leather, faded and frayed; termite damage. Additional descriptive data: Text in black ink, marked words and underlining in; various smaller leaves laid in. (Box 11)
  The full name of the author is Kasim b. Seyh Isa b. Idris b. Halil el-vefa'i (?) el-Hanefi el-Antaki el-Seybani, d. 1437. Death date of author from DP, without reference.
  On prayers as well as prophetic reports and stories, gathered from a number of authorities such as Envar ül-âsikîn and tefsir-i Abi'l-leys.